Guide to the Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company Records 1910-1938
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company Records
1910-1938
Montana State University-Bozeman Library, Merrill G Burlingame Special Collections P.O. Box 173320 Bozeman, MT 59717-3320 United States Phone (406) 994-4242 Fax (406) 994-2851 http://www.lib.montana.edu/archives/ University Archivist spcoll@www.lib.montana.edu
Collection 0869, MtBC, us
Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company
3 cubic feet
The Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company Records consist of financial ledgers, daybooks, and other business records of the various Livingston based Lehrkind operations, including firms that were absorbed by the company such as the Park Bottling Works and the Livingston Ice Company.
Biographical Note
Julius Lehrkind was a German immigrant who came to America in 1860. He opened a brewery in Davenport, Iowa, with his brother, Fred. There he married Emelie Lambach and had six children. Fred married Emelie's sister, Bertha, and had four children. Fred and Bertha died young, so Julius and Emelie took charge of their children. Emelie died in 1897. Julius married Emelie's niece, Lina Lambach, in 1899 and they had a son. Julius died in 1922. Julius sold his brewery in Iowa and moved to Bozeman in March 1895, bringing his extended family and a crew of experienced brewers with him. He bought the Spieth and Krug Brewery that same year, moved it to the north end of town, and renamed it the Bozeman Brewery. During Prohibition, the Lehrkinds ran the Lehrkind Coal and Pure Ice Company out of the building and had branch operations in Livingston, Montana to which most of the records in this collection pertain.
Primarily financial records of the various Livingston based Lehrkind operations, including firms that were absorbed by the company such as the Park Bottling Works and the Livingston Ice Company.
This collection is open for research.
Financial ledgers, daybooks, and other business records pertaining to the Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company were donated to Montana State University by Chan Libby of Livingston Montana on June 10, 1970. This collection was subsequently reported to the National Union Catalog of Manuscript Collections and assigned entry number 79-676.
Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company -- Archives
Beverage industry -- Montana -- History
Business and Corporations; Montana
Business records -- Montana
- (Box 1)
  - Livingston Ice Company
    (2 ledgers)
  - Daybook, 1908; 1910
  - Account Book, 1910
    (very few entries)
  - Order books, 1919; 1923; 1926; 1927; 1928; 1929; 1930; 1931
    1928 (2 books); 1929 (3 books); 1930 (2 books); 1931 (5 books)
- (Box 2)
  - Order books, 1932; 1922; 1934; 1935; 1935-1936; 1934-1937; 1936; 1937; 1938
    1922 (2 books); 1934 (3 books); 1935 (2 books); 1936 (2 books); 1937 (2 books); 1938 (4 books)
  - Park Bottling Works: customer book, 1929
  - Lehrkind Coal Company and Park Bottling Works: telegraph duplicate book, 1938
  - Lehrkind Coal and Ice Company, duplicate scale book, 1934-1938
- (Box 3)
  - Ledger: Coal and Ice, 1922-1927
  - Coal reports, 1935-1938
    (shows types of coal sold)
  - Ledger: ice, 1922-1928; 1933-1937; 1938
    (3 books)
  - Park Bottling works: Ledger, 1925-1932
  - Park Bottling works: account ledger, 1933-1938